<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Maxim Mikhaylov</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Maxim Mikhaylov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ALLES! CTF 2020 Writeup: Pyjail ATricks</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/alles-ctf-2020-writeup-pyjail-atricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/alles-ctf-2020-writeup-pyjail-atricks/</guid>
      <description>Description Category: Misc
Difficulty: Easy
Author: explo1t
Description: Run the secret function you must! Hrrmmm. A flag maybe you will get.
Overview This challenge takes place in a remote restricted Python shell a.k.a. a Python jail. Usually the goal is to escape the jail, i.e. to shell out and find the flag in the filesystem.
But this challenge description says that one may get a flag by running a secret function inside the jail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backing up Android with BorgBackup</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/backing-up-android-with-borgbackup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/backing-up-android-with-borgbackup/</guid>
      <description>Is there a simple way to backup non-rooted Android phone to a Borg repo? Since the phone is non-rooted, this greatly limits the kind of files that can be accessed and backed up. For instance, if you want to backup a Google Authenticator database, root is needed to access/data/data/com.google.android.apps.authenticator2/databases/databases (see this Android Stack Exchange question). But if you want to only backup data from device user storage, then root is not needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BorgBackup on macOS</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/borgbackup-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 18:10:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/borgbackup-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>Does the dandelion drop all its seeds at the base of its stalk? Does the cuckoo lay its eggs in one nest? So long as your backups are in one place, you are vulnerable to the fortunes of the world.
- The Tao of Backup
  Time Machine works well for local backups on macOS. Recently, I did an inventory of my data assets and came to the conclusion that it would be best to have an off-site backup of my data, in addition to a local Time Machine backup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensembling ConvNets using Keras</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/ensembling-convnets-using-keras/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/ensembling-convnets-using-keras/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally pusblished on Medium.com together with Towards Data Science.
 Introduction  &amp;ldquo;In statistics and machine learning, ensemble methods use multiple learning algorithms to obtain better predictive performance than could be obtained from any of the constituent learning algorithms alone. Unlike a statistical ensemble in statistical mechanics, which is usually infinite, a machine learning ensemble consists of only a concrete finite set of alternative models, but typically allows for much more flexible structure to exist among those alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking CAPTCHAs using a CNN</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/cnn-captcha-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/cnn-captcha-attack/</guid>
      <description>Introduction On one of my favorite wargame websites has a series of challanges on breaking CAPTCHA. It starts with a straightforward challange:
 Please enter the CAPTCHA backwards Time remaining: 10.00 seconds
 Since no distortions are introduced to the text and there are ~100 distinct shapes, there are plenty of ways to read the text off the image without resorting to machine learning.
The next one is even easier - only 12 distinct shapes:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
